[music]
Heat. Heat.
Congratulations. [music]
[music]
>> Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
>> On the substitutions.
>> Got to get familiar with my faces. Yeah.
Got
Well, welcome first off.
>> Congratulations.
>> Just curious when talking with Detroit
and other teams, how much was was your
versatility kind of part of part of the
conversation there and how much do you
think that that has helped you in this
process?
>> Yeah, I mean speaking with majority of
the teams that I spoke with or basically
all of them, um the versatility was
always brought up. Um I know how much
that that's valued in this league. Um
only 50 50 guys 53 guys can dress. So,
you know, having ability to play
multiple positions out there is always
an addition to a team is always going to
be something, you know, teams look for.
>> This was your first trip into free
agency. What were you looking for? What
what did you want to get out of it?
>> Um, I was looking for one a home. Um,
somewhere I felt, you know, comfortable
coming in every day playing football.
Um, a coaching staff that believed in
me. Um, that was that was important. and
um just you know having transparency
with the coaching staff and and the
everyday days and in in-n-out days of
you know what goes on you know to a game
plan and things like that. Um a city
that loves football and I believe I
found all of that in Detroit. You
>> explain maybe a little bit about the the
coaching staff believing in you. What
did Dan say? What did you hear from this
organization that told you that they you
know had a
>> Yeah. Um, you know, just when I got on
the phone with him, my first
conversation with him was that was a
heck of a football player. And, um,
playing Detroit these last three years,
four times in three years, it's almost
become like a division game. So, um,
just, you know, having the ability to go
against these guys and knowing what type
of outfit they are and how they going to
bring energy every time we play against
them. Um, that was something that that I
definitely took into account, you know,
when when choosing Detroit.
>> Did they realize uh any sort of vision
for how they see deploying you on the
field?
>> Um, not just yet. Um, again, versatility
was always a big thing. So having the
ability to play multiple positions, I'm
pretty sure I'll find a role.
>> Going back to Ruckers, I mean, you could
just see you lined up all over the
field. I'm just curious what what's your
favorite spot on the football field?
>> Um the football field. Being on it.
[laughter]
>> Yeah, just being on the football field.
That's honestly my favorite spot. You
know, teams do, you know, a lot of
things schematically to find ways to
move me around a lot. So just being on
the field for sure. You
>> talked to Isaiah Pacheco yesterday. What
can you tell us about him as a teammate
and a guy? I didn't see all of his
interview or all of it, but that's who
he is. Like he's he's he's 100% every
time. Um, since the day I met him, we
came in the same class. So, um, a guy
with a with a huge story, you know. Um,
but you would never know from all the
energy he brings. Um, he's like the how
he is yesterday, that's how he is every
day. So, you can expect that from him.
>> You come from a winning program in
Tampa. What do you think that you
learned over there that you can bring to
here to help, you know, the Lions
continue to, you know, push forward in
the playoffs?
>> Yeah. Um, you know, I think just being,
you know, being myself. I think, uh,
being myself, um, being a communicator,
you know, being a good teammate, um,
being a good person. Um, you know, but
also having that grit, that dog
mentality. Um, and I think that's
something that's already here and I'm
just here to add to it.
>> What was your first impression of the
conversation with Shep and just being
able to work with him now and and just
maybe how he sees that defense running
[clears throat] and and your fit within
it? Yeah, that was probably the realest
conversation I had with a coach since
I've been to league. You know, even
interviews prior to the league. So, um
that was a really good conversation. Um
we had some really good talks about, you
know, how they plan on using me and and
different things like that.
>> What about that conversation made it so
real?
>> Um just his transparency, you know, and
again, that was something I was looking
for in the free agency market. Um
coaches to be transparent and um he's
just a real guy. You know what I'm
saying? That's what players, you know,
players reciprocate to that. So,
>> use everywhere or you say want you a
slot or safety or
>> he didn't say he didn't say no.
>> You were involved in a pretty intense
camp battle last year. Um led to maybe a
smaller role than you would have wanted,
but how how do you feel like last year
um maybe enhances the urgency um to to
prove that you are who you believe you
are?
>> Yeah. Um you know, last year a lot of
things didn't go the way I thought it
would or the way I wanted it to. Um I
kind of put that in the past. um use it
as fuel for, you know, motivation for
this year coming up. Um again, I do see
myself as a starter in this league and I
said that last year and I'll say it
again. So, just having the ability to
come out here and compete.
>> Last time you played these guys, you you
picked off Jared. What else about that
game uh stands out to you?
>> Um as I told a lot of my peers after
that game, that was probably the most
intense game that I've played in my
career and it still stands to this day.
um going against the Lions is always
that that that environment, but uh just
being in for field and and having those
fans behind them and behind me now, um
it's always just a crazy environment and
um us being able to pull that win out,
that was big. It was big for me and the
Booker Bucks at the time.
>> About the pick,
>> what I remember about it, um we were in
cover three. I was a buzz safety and I
was ready to jump another route, but I
seen uh Levante hit his arm or something
and the ball literally just fell into my
hands.
>> You got
>> I do. I doubt it still. Yeah, I got all
of them. Yeah.
>> Beyond the uh the versatility,
Christian, what what do you think is
your best attribute on the field?
>> I'm a leader. Uh I think I'm I'm a
communicator. That's something I pride
myself on. Um football's hard. It's it's
an 11man sport and you know, you're not
always going to be in the best call. you
know that you you know you want to be in
or you know to go against the offense
that you're going against. So just
having guys and being able to
communicate with you and and have
somebody out there that you trust being
out there with and that's something I
want to be for this team.
>> One of the things they tried to
implement here under Shepard last year
was having I guess more fluidity with
the players calling the defense and
adjusting the defense. It seemed like a
lot for the guys to take in but as they
adjusted to it it seemed to be more
player driven. Um the communication
skills does that that appeal to you?
that ability to kind of modify calls on
the fly to to what you're seeing.
>> Yeah, I mean, as needed, like I'm not
going to go out there and just make up
calls, but no, as needed. Um, you know,
if coach wants to check, you know, made
to a certain look, then, you know, I'm
going to make make sure it's my
responsibility, you know, to make sure
get get us in the right call, you know,
have guys 11 guys playing fast and
flying to the football.
>> Have any other teammates reached out to
you?
>> Um, teammates? Um, no, not just yet. Um,
well, PCO I seen PCO yesterday when I
first got here, so that's always
exciting to see him. But, um, no, not
just yet. I spoke to Barnes. He
congratulated me. I trained with him,
but uh, not just yet. Just those two.
>> The same thing. I was just going to ask
if you had any previous relationship
with Brian Branch or Kirby Joseph, just
from NFL circles kind of.
>> No, I haven't. No, not at all. Playing
against them. A heck of a players, you
know, just watching those guys. I watch
those guys on film. I try to take
[music] little things from their game,
but um, no, not no personal
relationships just yet. No. How much was
uh evaluating the defense and the
personnel part of the decision too? You
know, you get look at guys like Hutch,
right? All pro, Campbell, all pro.
Kirby, you know, Bryant that Dave just
talked about. How much was that part of
the decision? How much you looking
forward to joining the unit?
>> Um, it was a big decision and I think
that's a product of the coaching. You
know, um, those guys are tremendous
athletes and tremendous players, but,
you know, I think that's a a great
product of what, you know, what great
coaching, you know, attributes to and
again, that's something I want to be a
part of, you know, going forward. just
good coaching and I think you [music]
know great coaches lead to great
players. So
>> seemed like you played really well as a
rookie when you played sorry right here.
Yes.
>> When you played mostly in the slot as a
rookie seemed like maybe that was your
your best season today at least
production wise. What about playing that
spot on the field do you feel like suits
your game the most?
>> Um anytime I think I'm close to the
football or you know close to the line
of scrimmage you know I can have an
impact whether that's blitzing covering
you know playing zone playing man. Um,
being close to the football is always,
you know, a plus, you know, somebody
like me. Um, I'm not the biggest guy on
the field. I know that. So, I got to
find ways to be effective, you know,
using my speed, using my athleticism to
be able to affect the game.
>> Going from being [clears throat]
undrafted to being a a big- time
contributor, like how has that shaped
you and your um mindset, your
perspective and all those things?
>> Um, coming from high school, I was a I
was a December offer to Ruckers. So, I
was probably one of the last people to
get an offer to Ruckers. Uh, I remember
it the day I got it and
probably two games left in the season.
So, since I've been there and going
from, you know, high school to being the
last commit in college and then going
from competing [music] with a fifth year
senior in college and going through all
of that, become a four-year starter, you
know, had the career I did at Ruckers
and then going from undrafted player, no
combine invite. I've been through just
about everything that a player can be
told that he couldn't do. So, just being
here today, I'm a product of that. free
agency. Is that part of it? I mean, you
know, was there another people telling
you you couldn't do something or last
year? Is that that the next iteration of
that? You know,
>> I mean, since, you know, since I've been
playing, I've been always, you know, I
always haven't been the biggest guy. So,
since I've been playing in high school,
you know, I'm from New York, I played
ball in New York, frowned upon, um went
to Jersey, um stood out, and then came
back to New York to finish high school.
So, uh you know, just I've been told no
a lot of times, and I've worked through
it. So, you know, just having the
ability to, you know, believe in myself,
that's the most important attribute for
me.
>> You I asked Larry Barn this yesterday.
This is the first year players could
have like Zoom calls during free agency
with the teams. Did you have any of
those? And how did that Okay. No, not
that. What other teams were you
considering in free agency?
>> Um, I was considering a handful. I mean,
not I mean, I left it honestly to my
agent. I just, you know, I asked him I
told him I want the best opportunity for
me, [music] you know, as a player, but
also, you know, I want to win. You know,
that's something I pride myself. I don't
we don't do all of this hard work to you
know go places not to win. So definitely
[music]
>> around some really great veterans in the
secondary in Tampa and Jamal and Carlton
Davis and and Antoine. You just I'm just
curious what kind of impact they've had
in shaping your your young career.
>> Yeah. Um from the moment I stepped into
the league, I I've been I've been
watching Antoine um since college. We
had the same um college coach. Um he was
at Minnesota and he came to Ruckers my
senior year. So, I've been watching him
since college and I played the nickel my
senior year. So, I watch a lot of his
film. Um, he's been great, you know,
just, you know, helping, you know,
little things on the field. Um, we're
similar, we're similar in build, so like
he, you know, helps me find ways to, you
know, affect the game and and be a, you
know, just be a menace on the field.
And, um, other guys like Dean, super
smart vet, teaching guys how to take
care of their body, you know, Carlton
helping off the field stuff, you know,
just all of those guys have different
effects. So,
you
>> talked to CD at all before?
>> I actually I just seen CD a couple days
ago. Yeah, it was funny. We were talking
about it before I even, you know,
decided to come here, but he was telling
me about Detroit and, you know, all the
good things. So,
>> yeah.
>> All right. Thank you.
>> Appreciate it.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Heat.